Howard Leung

Web Developer

ABOUT ME

I'm a self-taught coder with experience in creating full-stack applications using React, NodeJS, and MongoDB. I have a good grasp on the web development fundamentals: HTML, CSS, and Javascript, and I'm confident that I would be able to learn any new technologies required.

By working on full-stack personal projects, I have gained experience in various aspects of web development, to include: idea and conception, wire-frames and planning, UI/UX design, front-end code, back-end code, and deployment procedures. What I enjoy most about web development is learning many different skills, and putting them all together to create a cohesive finished product.

PROJECT

IntegrationPOS - https://integrationpos.herokuapp.com

IntegrationPOS is a personal project that I created to practice web development. It's an all-in-one system designed to help small-business restaurants bring their businesses online. My goal for this project was to gain perspective on the entire full-stack development process.

Features of IntegrationPOS include:

- A public online storefront with a cart system for receiving online orders.
- A products manager for maintaining product data like images, quantities, online/offline statuses, and categories.
- An order management system which receives orders and displays them to the user as itemized "order tickets".
- A built-in POS system which allows the store owner to create/edit orders in-house, and push order tickets to the order manager.
- Order and product modifiers for further customization (i.e. extra ingredients, size).
- A theme editor where users can change their storefront's colors, fonts, and images.
- A curbside-pickup scheduling system which enables the store owner to offer curbside services to their customers, as well as control the flow and rate of orders.
- A subscription system to receive payments for service from IntegrationPOS customers.

Skills I learned:

- Full-stack CRUD operations utilizing MVC architecture
- REST API creation and consumption
- Working with MongoDB designing and creating schema models, queries, creating/updating/saving/deleting documents
- Front-end and back-end implementation of external APIs and libraries
- Separation of concerns and modular code
- Debugging errors by recreating problems and finding solutions
- UI/UX design
- Creating reusable and mobile-responsive React components
- React-router and Redux
- Local storage/session storage
- User authentication via OAuth method and JSON web tokens
- Data validation
- CSS animations
- Real-time data via websockets (Socket.io)
- Deployment to Heroku

98-862 Iliee St. Aiea, HI 96701 (808) 386-4615 hwrdleung@gmail.com

PORTFOLIO

https://hwrdleung.github.io/

EDUCATION

University of Hawaii at Manoa BA Entrepreneurship

AUGUST 2011 - MAY 2014

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JAVASCRIPT (ES6)

REACT/REDUX

NODEJS

EXPRESS

MONGODB

NPM

GIT

GITHUB

REST API

DEBUGGING

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sale Lake Chinese Restaurant JUNE 2020 - PRESENT Busser

Arancino Di Mare

JANUARY 2013 - FEBRUARY 2016 Busser/Food runner

Longhi's Restaurant

JANUARY 2013 - JANUARY 2015 Busser